<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>brain of dane</title><link href="http://www.brainofdane.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.brainofdane.com/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.brainofdane.com/</id><updated>2013-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>utility apps</title><link href="http://www.brainofdane.com/utility-apps.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dane Henson</name></author><id>tag:www.brainofdane.com,2013-03-12:utility-apps.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I (maybe even we, if you agree) have had my view of software completely redefined recently.  It started happening after I bought my first smart phone.  The shift was very subtle until it hit me in the face the other day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking for an "app"; not an application, because that's so '90's.  I wanted to try out this &lt;a href="http://www.pomodorotechnique.com/"&gt;Pomodoro Technique&lt;/a&gt; everyone talks about.  The technique is super simple and all you need is a countdown timer that will count down from 25 minutes.  You work for 25 minutes, then every 25 minutes you take a break for 5 or 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't need an "app" to do it, just a timer.  Well, in my newly twisted view of the world, there is an app for everything and gosh darn it, there are about 10 billion different Pomodoro apps.  You can't just have one.  Everyone wants their app to be just a little bit different than the rest.  Better probably... maybe...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I call these utility apps.  I remember when the iPhone first started gaining popularity and "there's an app for that" became a thing.  A new kind of app emerged with multiple utilities rolled into one: compass, level, timer, alarm, 'flashlight', etc.  It was all kind of ridiculous, but people loved it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think utility apps are a bad thing.  Even after realizing the futility of having both a timer and a Pomodoro app on my phone, I still wanted the right one for the job.  A simple timer isn't pre-set for 25 minutes.  It doesn't have a preset for short breaks, and long breaks.  Okay, those are silly reasons, but that still didn't stop me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I find refreshing is that these utility apps breed refinement.  The Pomodoro craze might not be the best example.  Some of the worst offenders in the software industry are e-mail clients.  I understand that some people can't live without the beast that is Outlook, but my work laptop seems to run 50% slower because of that stupid 300-pound gorilla.  Instead of building a monolithic e-mail/calendar/todo list/coffee maker, you build a &lt;a href="http://www.yorba.org/geary/"&gt;really good e-mail client&lt;/a&gt; that does just that and refine it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure there are plenty of fruitless endeavors out there, but making an "app" can't be all that bad.  I've &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/agenda-tasks"&gt;done it myself&lt;/a&gt; from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>giving back</title><link href="http://www.brainofdane.com/giving-back.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dane Henson</name></author><id>tag:www.brainofdane.com,2013-03-09:giving-back.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been a Linux user since 2001.  Back then, I just thought it was a fun toy.  I wanted it to be something I could use daily, but my undeveloped high school brain couldn't find a good use for it.  Honestly, I just like tinkering without bounds.  Twelve years later, I have grown a lot and I find that most of my work can get done faster, easier, and exactly the way I would like if I just do it on a Linux box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obvious'd... I know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, my time is very valuable to me.  Therefore, I value the time others put into developing the software I use.  Unfortunately, I don't always have to money to match that value.  For instance, I use inkscape to create images for my own personal use.  Inkscape's proprietary rivals can cost $400 or more for a version that will probably be obsolete by next year.  Though the software may not be worth quite that much, I imagine the people who develop Inkscape would love a slice of that kind of pie.  Developers are not wrong to want compensation for their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I have no money to give, I give praise and constructive feedback.  I file bugs and try to help squash them, or at the very least triage.  I really hope that's enough, because though a lot of the work I do is both private and personal, I wouldn't be able to do it without the contributions of these great developers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>restless</title><link href="http://www.brainofdane.com/restless.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dane Henson</name></author><id>tag:www.brainofdane.com,2013-03-02:restless.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've switched my blog... again.  This time it's powered by Pelican, and it doesn't have comments.  If you want to talk, find me on one of the many social networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I should be content with what I have, but it's so hard not to get restless after a while.  First it was learning to program again, then it was learning how to write a GUI, then it was back to writing a book.  November was when I stopped feeling as wrestless.  I put &lt;a href="http://launchpad.net/agenda"&gt;Agenda&lt;/a&gt; aside for a little down time while I participated in &lt;a href="http://www.nanowrimo.org"&gt;NaNoWriMo&lt;/a&gt;.  It was a relief to stop thinking in source code all the time, but it was stressful trying to write up a fictional world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start of the year, I funneled a ton of energy into getting a little web series off the ground, but I'm stalled out on that now too.  The desire is there, but my wife and I lack the time and energy to keep the ball rolling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I'm back at it again trying to figure out what it is I want to do with the precious little time I have.  I'm learning a little Python, I'm pretty much done with Ruby, I'm wanting to do something personally significant maybe.  That's not to say I'm unhappy.  I'm very happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just feel restless.  All pent up with nowhere to go.  Maybe if I blog regularly, I can straighten out my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>unofficial elementary faq</title><link href="http://www.brainofdane.com/unofficial-elementary-faq.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Dane Henson</name></author><id>tag:www.brainofdane.com,2012-10-21:unofficial-elementary-faq.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The official elementary Answers system has been removed, which is awesome!  Why is that awesome?  It means the moderation team gets a little break from answering questions! (yay)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, what it means is the elementary counsil has seen fit to retire Jupiter and start gearing up for a Luna release.  If you peruse elementaryos.org, you will see that they have made it much more difficult to find the download page for Jupiter and when you do get to the downloads page, you will see a placeholder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, now that there is no place for people to ask questions, I thought it would be fitting to put up an unofficial FAQ.  Since I would normally be answering these questions on the official site, you're basically getting official answers--unofficially.  If you have any suggestions, feel free to let me know in the comments.  I know I haven't covered everything here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we go...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Questions About 0.1 (Jupiter):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Where can I get jupiter?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, you probably don't want to use Jupiter unless you really know what you're doing.  It has officially reached end of life, and will no longer receive security updates.  The official elementary apps are not receiving updates either.  While it is still a beautiful system, you are probably better off just waiting for Luna.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are still not deterred, the official page is still up for historical purposes: &lt;a href="http://elementaryos.org/jupiter"&gt;Jupiter Download Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Should I upgrade Jupiter to the latest version of Ubuntu?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NO!  If the update manager pops up and says there is a new version of the operating system available, DO NOT UPGRADE!  This was an issue from the earliest release of Jupiter and will give you a headache if you let it perform the upgrade.  You may continue to upgrade packages, but do not do a full distribution upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How do I customize XX and YY on my desktop?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all support has been pulled from the elementary website and there is still hope for those of you wanting to tweak your Jupiter desktop.  Just visit the &lt;a href="http://elementaryos.org/docs/user-guide"&gt;elementary OS User Guide&lt;/a&gt; and learn about all of the wonderful things you can do to your desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Will I be able to upgrade directly from Jupiter to Luna?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, that will not be an option in the elementary installer.  The elementary dev team just does not have the appropriate resources to build and test an upgrade system of that magnitude and the two releases are just too far apart to be compatible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a faithful and loyal user of Jupiter, we salute you and we are grateful for your support.  I recommend that you make multiple backups of your '/home' directory and any other important documents you might have on your system and perform a clean install when Luna is released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Questions About 0.2 (Luna):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;When Will Luna Be Released?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://elementaryos.org/journal/when-its-ready"&gt;When it's ready!&lt;/a&gt; (TM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luna is nearing a Beta release as of this writing and you can track the progress of the Beta1 milestone on the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/elementary/+milestone/luna-beta1"&gt;launchpad page&lt;/a&gt;.  If you have what it takes to knock out those bugs, please do so.  I want to see Luna released just as bad as you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why doesn't the elementary team have a steady release cycle?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question is way too loaded to fully answer right here.  If you would like to read about why they haven't released Luna yet, refer to my &lt;a href="http://www.brainofdane.com/blog/2012/10/05/elementary-cant-afford-a-bug-bomb/"&gt;earlier post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Where Can I Get the Luna Daily?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you download the daily and use it on a production machine, kittens will die, civilizations will collapse, and your girlfriend will leave you.  I know it seems stable, but the elementary team only wants experienced testers and developers using the dailies.  You will &lt;i&gt;only&lt;/i&gt; receive support from the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/elementaryos"&gt;launchpad platform&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have given you the obvious disclaimer, I will give you the link to the download page.  With great power comes great responsibility.  Use it wisely.
&lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/elementaryos/files/unstable/"&gt;Luna daily downloads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>a pear-shaped form of flattery</title><link href="http://www.brainofdane.com/a-pear-shaped-form-of-flattery.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Dane Henson</name></author><id>tag:www.brainofdane.com,2012-10-08:a-pear-shaped-form-of-flattery.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been said that imitation is the sincerest form of flattery.  Usually, that saying comes riding the tail or a complaint like, "Mommy, he's copying meeee."  It is meant to sooth the person being copied and in some cases deter the copycat by implying some sort of underlying affection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, a Linux distribution by the name of "Pear Linux" started spreading like wildfire through the elementary community.  Why?  Because "they're copying us!"  It's no secret, either&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not as smooth or as polished as elementary has come to be, but it is there.  Pear OS clearly uses a form of Gala for window management, wingpanel, and a few other elementary packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past few days, I have been struggling with whether or not I should share my thoughts on this issue.  I was concerned that the mere mention of Pear Linux would send hordes of elementary users running to their website to download, install, and test their OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the last thing I want to do is give them more credence than they deserve just by attempting to decry their very existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fear is that we would send elementary zealots at them who would then try to burn their website to the ground with fiery insults and outlandish claims.  Please, forgive me for thinking this of you.  I realize that we are all mature human beings here and I ask that we act civilized to our fellow open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pear is But a Shadow&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has become clear that the creator of Pear OS is only a one-man team with a relatively small user base.  The elementary team has always been a veritable skeleton crew compared to some of the larger Linux counterparts, but the Pear OS "team" is miniscule in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the very talented team of developers and designers at elementary, they are able to put together a much more polished experience and pay great attention to details.  It is more than just a hobby, it is a full-fledged project.  That alone gives elementary a huge leg up on these smaller OS compilations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Pear OS is doing is pulling all of the pieces of elementary that have been developed in-house and remixing them in a way that is pleasing to the developer.  He even uses Ubuntu as a base.  Isn't that we want?  Recognition?  Remixing? Repackaging for multiple distributions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, redistributing elementary packages is fine until you start changing names and source code without following GPL licensing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pear is a Non-threat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The elementary developers themselves have been very clear in stating that they do not feel threatened or upset by the existence of Pear OS.  Their main concern is that the creator is in violation of the GPL, which governs the usage of the individual elementary projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is my understanding that the elementary team plans to work with the developer to fix any GPL violations.  As long as he cooperates and operates within the bounds of the Licensing, there won't be any hard feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the open source spirit, I wish him luck in his endeavor..&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>elementary can't afford a bug bomb</title><link href="http://www.brainofdane.com/elementary-cant-afford-a-bug-bomb.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Dane Henson</name></author><id>tag:www.brainofdane.com,2012-10-05:elementary-cant-afford-a-bug-bomb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear elementary OS Fanatic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, it's frustrating.  Luna is right there within grasp.  You are probably downloading the "unstable" daily and you have realized that it isn't as unstable as the devs might have you believe.  You run it on a daily basis to do real work (as I am now), but the elementary council just won't release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Tale of the Power User&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;But there aren't any bugs!!!&lt;/i&gt; you scream, raging at the comments section on the latest drool-inducing journal post.  &lt;i&gt;I'm using it right now, and it's as stable as a rock!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there is that one little annoyance where you stick your favorite kitty wallpaper on your desktop and behold, &lt;a href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/pantheon-greeter/+bug/1061235"&gt;you can't see it on the login screen&lt;/a&gt;.  Instead, it's defaulting to that beautiful cloudy scene you remember from good old Jupiter.  &lt;i&gt;That's okay, I'll deal with it for now&lt;/i&gt; you decide.  That is, &lt;a href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/pantheon-greeter/+bug/1036484"&gt;until you try to read the current time&lt;/a&gt;.  White on white just doesn't work for reading text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Well, I'll just install the wallpaper to the system wallpaper directory so that my kitty picture is available globally.&lt;/i&gt;  you say.  That would be fine until your mom sees what you've done and asks why she can't have her own picture on the login screen.  &lt;i&gt;It's not that simple, mom.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see where I'm going with that scenario?  All of these little annoyances add up to larger issues that can't be solved by an average user.  I don't know if you've noticed, but the elementary team is indeed targeting the average user, while trying not to alienate the power user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Bugs That Aren't Bugs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been seeing a trend in comments on the elementary OS journal that say something like: "Why don't you just release?  There aren't any major bugs, and if there are, you can just have the users report them and you can update the PPA when you get it fixed."  This is what I would call a "Bug Bomb."  Drop a somewhat buggy distro on the unsuspecting populace and hope that they bomb it with bug reports until it gets sufficiently cleaned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, you want my grandma to report a bug?  If I install elementary OS to a relative's computer, it had better work like butter or I'll be answering calls all day long about system crashes or disappearing windows/buttons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second, and biggest issue I have with that statement has to do with the fact that the Designers are at the top of the food chain in the elementary community.  If the Designers aren't happy, nobody is happy.  This is where the "bug that isn't a bug" comes in.  Developers and Power Users both have a similar view of bugs.  To them, bugs are issues that cause software to crash, or cause certain GUI elements to lock up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you were to examine the launchpad bugs, you would find that a majority of them pertain to how the user interacts with the system.  I'm not saying that these aren't bugs from a technical standpoint.  What I am saying is that a power user would overlook a lot of those small details because he/she is going to tweak the hell out of the system anyway.  Most distributions are written for Power Users by Power Users, with little focus on how all of the pieces fit together.  In elementary's case, the bar has been raised.  If a transition doesn't feel right or a button is a few pixels off, there'll be hell to pay, bugs are filed and developers get to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designers, User Experience experts, and Developers of elementary are calling for more than just an amalgamation of hodgepodge software.  They are working towards an insanely beautiful user experience and that is why the "minor" bugs have become paramount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lessons Learned, No More Bug Bombs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn't here when Jupiter was released, but I have heard enough from the developers to know that they have some regrets about how it all turned out.  I think they feel like the initial release was rushed.  Having used Jupiter myself before joining the community, I can vouch for the fact that it was a little rough around the edges.  We are still experiencing fallout from the great "dist-upgrade" debacle that caused quite a few people to have to re-install their systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From these experiences, the developers have learned that it is better to have an airtight release image than release and fix bugs later.  This means no more buggy dist-upgrades (if in fact they decide to enable dist-upgrades by default), no more kernel panics, and no more crashy default web browsers.  Of course, time has passed and much of the software has matured beyond these kinds of bugs more common among initial releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hope is that the elementary OS user community can understand the painstaking work going on behind the scenes to release a smooth, tightly integrated computing experience.  After all of the effort put into the user experience, elementary just can't afford a bug bomb.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>