<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Brain of Dane</title>
    <link>http://brainofdane.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Brain of Dane</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://brainofdane.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories of Dragons</title>
      <link>http://brainofdane.com/posts/stories-of-dragons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brainofdane.com/posts/stories-of-dragons/</guid>
      <description>I could spend hours telling you stories about my kids. They are lovable, funny, smart, and downright amazing. I don&amp;rsquo;t broadcast those stories here or on social media because some people love to listen, while others just glaze over when I talk about kids. Know your audience, right?
We have a &amp;ldquo;third&amp;rdquo; son who is no longer living with us. He went back to his biological father. Last we heard, he is doing very well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Flight</title>
      <link>http://brainofdane.com/posts/test-flight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brainofdane.com/posts/test-flight/</guid>
      <description>I think all boys and girls start life with a fascination for flight. Well, that may not be the case, but it just seems so natural to me. You start out not really caring about anything but cars and trucks and ponies until a jumbo jet shoots past overhead and you look up. I was there one of the first times my firstborn son looked up at the sky wondering what that noise was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on elementary Packaging</title>
      <link>http://brainofdane.com/posts/thoughts-on-elementary-packaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brainofdane.com/posts/thoughts-on-elementary-packaging/</guid>
      <description>This is my rudimentary understanding of the evolution of package management in Linux, and why it&amp;rsquo;s still a problem for the average user.
In the beginning, there was source code. If you wanted an application on Linux, you went out, grabbed the &amp;ldquo;tarball&amp;rdquo; (the Linux equivalent of a zip/compressed folder) and compiled the source code on your machine. If that application required any other software, you had to download that and compile it too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fathering</title>
      <link>http://brainofdane.com/posts/fathering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brainofdane.com/posts/fathering/</guid>
      <description>Before my firstborn was even a twinkle in my eye, there were always thousands of doubts in my head about whether I would make a good dad. I’m sure it’s not just me. Everyone wakes up every morning with a new pile of doubts to add to their ever-growing collection of insecurities. Mine just happen to revolve around someone that barely even knows how to read.
Priorities In the beginning, it was all about security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Networking</title>
      <link>http://brainofdane.com/posts/social-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brainofdane.com/posts/social-networking/</guid>
      <description>This social media thing is tiring. Back when Facebook was a University-only network, I was a big fan and a frequent user. I also jumped on the Twitter bandwagon in the early days when people thought it was a stupid fad. I remember setting it up to tweet from my flip-phone via SMS. That was the coolest. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t own the first gen iPhone, but I sure as hell could &amp;ldquo;tweet&amp;rdquo; with the rest of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo2013</title>
      <link>http://brainofdane.com/posts/nanowrimo-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brainofdane.com/posts/nanowrimo-2013/</guid>
      <description>In November, a bunch of lemmings get together and jump off a cliff. It&amp;rsquo;s called NaNoWriMo and I&amp;rsquo;ll be joining those lemmings.
Every year, writers from all over the world take the entire month of November to write 50,000 words of a novel. While I may not be the best writer, I like a challenge and I have a few stories that I need to share. Even if it means just sharing them with myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Tex</title>
      <link>http://brainofdane.com/posts/big-tex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brainofdane.com/posts/big-tex/</guid>
      <description>I took Caleb to the Texas state fair this week. It was raining, cold (for Texas), and kind of miserable. We actually had a blast despite all of the negatives. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s the fair. How could you not have fun?
Highlight 1 - The Train We rode the train. Caleb absolutely loves riding the train. We get to cruise down the tracks at 80 mph, and we don&amp;rsquo;t have to be buckled in!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baby I Miss You</title>
      <link>http://brainofdane.com/posts/baby-i-miss-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brainofdane.com/posts/baby-i-miss-you/</guid>
      <description>Baby, I miss you and I haven&amp;rsquo;t even met you yet.
Yesterday was the due date, but nothing happened. I know birth is completely unpredictable, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard not to set some expectations. Two weeks ago, we were totally ready to go. We had no doubt that Eli would be born any minute. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure.
It seems like every day, Shari tells me she feels different. Today could be the day, tomorrow could be the day, right this second she&amp;rsquo;s probably having a contraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Your Gal</title>
      <link>http://brainofdane.com/posts/know-your-gal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brainofdane.com/posts/know-your-gal/</guid>
      <description>We started taking birthing classes a few weeks ago. This is our second baby, but it will be our first home birth, so it is required by our midwife.
Going through a birth once is enough to sear it in your brain. It is the most beautiful, interesting, horrible thing I have ever done. It&amp;rsquo;s both exciting and terrifying. When it&amp;rsquo;s all over, it is worth every second, but you never want to do it again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bun In The Oven</title>
      <link>http://brainofdane.com/posts/bun-in-the-oven/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brainofdane.com/posts/bun-in-the-oven/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I have officially reached the point in our pregnancy that people like to call &amp;ldquo;Full Term&amp;rdquo;. Yes, the bun in the oven has baked long enough that he could come at any time.
I&amp;rsquo;m not freaking out.
I&amp;rsquo;m freaking out.
I&amp;rsquo;m not really freaking out.
I&amp;rsquo;m really freaking out.
I mean, we&amp;rsquo;ve done this before. We have a 3 year old that came out of my wife. We can do this again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dice Roll</title>
      <link>http://brainofdane.com/posts/dice-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brainofdane.com/posts/dice-roll/</guid>
      <description>The other day, I was researching a Role Playing Game rules system at work. Of course, the most famous RPG is Dungeons and Dragons. I was wanting something a little less intense that could be played during my lunch break with a couple of co-workers.
My research was successful as I stumbled across a rule set called Mini Six. While I was previewing the PDF, I made a big mistake. I accidentally printed the entire 34 page document&amp;hellip; in color.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Film Love</title>
      <link>http://brainofdane.com/posts/film-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brainofdane.com/posts/film-love/</guid>
      <description>This picture was taken on my Nikon FE. It used to be my sister&amp;rsquo;s film camera, before digital cameras were a thing. Somehow it got passed to me and I love using it.
Film has its charms and wiles that tend to ensnare the hearts of the romantics among us. It speaks to our emotional nature, making us&amp;ndash;the photographers&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;feel&amp;rdquo; the moment instead of just capturing it 10 different times and moving on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>